<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Isaac Reforged</name>
    <directory>isaac reforged</directory>
    <id>2349100735</id>
    <description>[h1]Isaac Reforged![/h1]
This mod aims to add and rebalance characters, synergies, and transformations, while remaining faithful to the vanilla experience.

Supports External Item Descriptions!
Supports Mod Config Menu!
Supports Revelations!
Supports Fiend Folio!
&amp; More!

All changes are configurable with the Mod Config Menu. (May require a restart during a run)

[h1]Features:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]A new trinket called the Right Hand, the holy counter to the Left Hand.
  [*]Eternal Chests will always pay out with something, and have a small chance to teleport you to an Angel Room.
  [*]I Found Pills gives a random pill effect.
  [*]Several Transformations have been buffed or modified.
  [*]All characters start with innate and starting trinkets.
  [*]The Lost never loses Holy Mantle on rerolls.
  [*]When Cain collects Cain's other eye, he gets 20/20 vision.
  [*]Troll Bombs will uniformly detonate after 2 seconds.
  [*]Tinted Ground, a once per floor opportunity to a crawlspace and a chance to enter the black market!
[/list]

[h1]Transformations:[/h1]
The Bob Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation
  [*]Bob's Bladder contributes to the transformation
[/list]
The Conjoined Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants an extra trinket slot
  [*]Gives the cancer trinket
[/list]
The Oh Crap Transformation 
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation
  [*]Butt Bombs, No. 2, Farting Baby, and Number One all additionally contribute to the transformation
[/list]
The Adult Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Depression
[/list]
The Spider Baby Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants Spider Bite, Spider Mod, and Spider Baby
[/list]
The Seraphim Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives the Soul
[/list]
The Fun Guy Transformation
[list]
  [*]Grants all passive items in the transformation except for God's Flesh
[/list]
The Beelzbub Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Muligan and 3 Pretty Flies
[/list]
The Duality Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives Duality and Eucharist
  [*]Achieved by holding the Left and Right Hands
[/list]
The Magneto Transformation
[list]
  [*]Gives all passive items in the transformation
  [*]Reflects 100% of enemy shots back at them
  [*]Achieved by collecting two of the following: Magneto, Strange Attractor, Metal Plate, Broken Magnet, and Super Magnet
[/list]

[h1]Starting Trinkets:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Isaac gets the effect of Golden Horse Shoe and starts with Bag Lunch
  [*]Magdalene gets the effect of Purple Heart and starts with Maggy's Faith
  [*]Cain gets the effect of Lucky Toe and starts with Paper Clip 
  [*]Judas gets the effect of Black Feather and starts with Judas' Tongue 
  [*]XXX gets the effect of Meconium and starts with Petrified Poop
  [*]Eve gets the effect of Daemon's Tail and starts with Wish Bone 
  [*]Samson gets the effect of Samson's Lock and starts with Child's Heart
  [*]Azazel gets the effect of A Missing Page and starts with Tape Worm
  [*]Lazarus gets the effect of Lost Cork and starts with Rosary Bead
  [*]Eden gets the effect of Error (404)
  [*]The Lost gets the Faded Polaroid and starts with Fragmented Card
  [*]Lilith gets the effect of Child Leash and starts with Blind Rage
  [*]The Keeper gets the effect of Rib of Greed and starts with Store Key
  [*]Apollyon gets the effect of Callus and starts with Locust of Conquest 
  [*]The Forgotten gets the effect of Crow Heart and starts with Finger Bone
[/list]

Let me know if you enjoy the mod, find any bugs, have any suggestions or criticisms!
</description>
    <version>1.6.3</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pills"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
    <tag id="Removals"/>
</metadata>
