<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Items Reforged</name>
    <directory>items reforged</directory>
    <id>2342471510</id>
    <description>[h1]Items Reforged![/h1]
This mod aims to rebalance and tweak items that would otherwise be detrimental to a run, while remaining faithful to the vanilla experience.

Supports External Item Descriptions!
Supports Mod Config Menu!
Supports Revelations!
Supports Fiend Folio!
&amp; More!

All changes are configurable with the Mod Config Menu. (May require a restart during a run)

[h1]Actives:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Breath of Life fires a high damage angelic laser in all 4 corners of the screen.
  [*]Glass Cannon has a faster cooldown, but briefly pauses firing tears upon use. All health is also converted to empty bone hearts.
  [*]Mine Crafter recharges over time and has a slight cooldown.
  [*]The Bean, Kidney Bean, and Mega Bean all recharges over time.
  [*]Mom's Pad requires 6 charges, and fears enemies for a longer duration.
  [*]Mom's Bra requires 4 charges, and slows enemies after the active petrify wears off.
  [*]Dead Sea Scrolls now picks from a list of 108 active items. The Clicker is excluded.
  [*]Scissors scales evenly with your damage and tear effects. Additionally, the item will spawn a long lasting creep.
  [*]The Poop will spawn a brown creep alongside a poop when used.
  [*]Hallowed Ground is now an active item that lets you choose where to place the white poop.
  [*]Monster Manual gives you extra familiars for the current floor.
  [*]Isaac's Tears has been reduced to 4 charges. Also this item was buffed in Booster pack #5 (Lesser known by players).
  [*]Necronomicon has been reduced to 4 charges. 
  [*]Dataminer, on top of its normal effects, has a chance (in ascending rarity) to spawn a game breaking bug, activate broken modem for a room, cause an error, or teleports you to the I AM ERROR room. The latter effect consumes the item.
  [*]Yum Heart will now progress through red hearts, soul hearts, black hearts, eternal hearts, and lastly lives. Prioritizes lowest tier of damaged health.
  [*]Plan C will now revive you as ???, only if you have the character unlocked.
  [*]Hourglass now slows enemies for an extended amount of time.
  [*]My Little Unicorn has been reduced to 4 charges.
  [*]Spider Butt scales with your damage.
  [*]Kamikaze scales with your item and bomb upgrades.
  [*]Friendly Ball has been reduced to 1 charge.
  [*]Wooden Nickel has a very rare chance to spawn a lucky penny.
[/list]

[h1]Passives:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Tiny Planet gives a slight tears up, range up, shotspeed down, and follows a more uniform orbit around Isaac.
  [*]Magneto has a 25% chance to reflect enemy shots back at them.
  [*]Dad's Lost Coin works much like Money = Power, except for luck. For every coin you have, you gain 0.1 luck.
  [*]Trisagion now curves up its -66% Damage Multiplier by using a secondary 33% Damage Multiplier.
  [*]Strange Attractor provides a 20% Damage Multiplier and pulls enemies towards the player less quickly.
  [*]Cursed Eye gives a +0.4 Damage up, and has a chance to spawn a troll bomb.
  [*]Dead Tooth's poison aura has a chance for killed enemies to drop black hearts.
  [*]Holy Water grants a splash damage tear effect that spawns creep, and has a 10% Damage Multiplier.
  [*]Missing Page 2 will proc on any health lost, causing slight mass room damage.
  [*]Little Baggy grants half a soul heart upon taking any pill.
  [*]God's Flesh will protect you from enemies that would otherwise explode, cause further enemies to spawn, or release shots. This effect however, will also override other death triggers, such as consumable drops.
  [*]Isaac's Heart calls out to its brothers, as a new tear effect that heavily increases heart drop chances. 
  [*]Fast Bombs grant a massive tears up to Dr. Fetus, and grants Marked to Epic Fetus.
  [*]3 Dollar Bill grants a substantial range up.
  [*]Technology 2 no longer gives you a damage down multiplier!
  [*]Common Cold now affects your familiars too.
  [*]Placenta will heal every 30 seconds.
  [*]Lucky Foot will help when you're just a bit short of a shop item, and give scaling movement speed based on player luck.
  [*]Black Bean makes your tears periodically pass gas.
  [*]Shard of Glass now deals contact damage and causes bleeding.
  [*]Poke-Go will rarely spawn in champions.
  [*]Magic 8 Ball have a 10% to spawn a card when getting hit. Additionally, every floor a fortune telling machine will spawn.
  [*]Betrayal will let you attack charmed enemies for x4 damage.
  [*]Deep pockets will have a 50% chance to drop either a card or pill when taking damage.
  [*]Glyph of balance will attempt to balance your consumables as you pick them up.
  [*]Aries damage scales with movement speed. Moving will slowly build up speed.
  [*]Broken Modem now has a 30% chance to negate incoming damage.
  [*]Three Dollar Bill counts as currency, effectively trippling the dollar.
  [*]Soy Milk is no longer affected by tears down, unless Libra is picked up.
[/list]

[h1]Familiars:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Abel fires low damage, stagnant tears that pierce.
  [*]Brother Bobby scales with your damage faster with a lower starting damage.
  [*]Sister Maggy scales with your damage slower with a higher starting damage.
  [*]Little C.H.A.D. will give one heart container upon acquisition.
  [*]Little Gish will give one black heart container upon acquisition.
  [*]Guppy's Hairball summons blue flies upon entering a new room, the amount less than or equal to the number of enemies.
  [*]Best Bud, when activated, will deal damage and block shots.
  [*]King Baby gathers your familiars around him, and always follows you into battle.
  [*]Bloodshot Eye now shoots tech lasers, instead of tears.
  [*]Rainbow Baby scales randomly with your damage.
  [*]Cain's Other Eye now shoots in the direction the player is firing, copying tear effects. Items such as brimstone, mom's knife, or ludovico will end this synergy. 
  [*]The Peeper will grant another peeper upon getting hit.
  [*]Ghost Baby scales with your damage.
  [*]Harlequin Baby scales with your damage.
  [*]Little Steven scales with your damage. If the trinket Baby-bender is held, Little Steven deals much more damage.
  [*]Farting Baby will always provide mass room poison, scaling with your damage.
  [*]Familiars that explode won't deal friendly fire damage. This includes Bob's Brain, BBF, 7 Seals, and Lil Delirium.
  [*]Punching Bag will now deal contact damage.
  [*]Key Bum now has better rewards based on total keys collected. Will also drop a battery upon taking a charged key.
  [*]Bum Friend now has a chance to repay the player over time. Will also give luck ups when taking a lucky penny.
[/list]

[h1]Item Pools:[/h1]
[list]
  [*]Magneto has been added to the Shop item pool.
  [*]Dad's Ring and Hallowed Ground have been added to the Angel room item pool.
[/list]

Let me know if you enjoy the mod, find any bugs, have any suggestions or criticisms!
</description>
    <version>2.0</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
    <tag id="Removals"/>
</metadata>
